Guide to the James Joyce Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- SERIES III. SPECIAL FILES, 1884-1969; (36 boxes)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT PLACES ASSOCIATED WITH JOYCE
    - Archbishop Marsh's Library, Dublin (Box 24, Folder 510)
    - Davy Byrne's Pub, Dublin (Box 24, Folder 511)
    - Café Voltaire, Paris (Box 24, Folder 512)
    - Misc. (Box 24, Folder 513)
    - Misc. (Box 24, Folder 514)
  - LEGAL DOCUMENTS, MISCELLANEA
    - Harrington, John F. Prescription for eye lotion for Joyce 1931 Aug 6 (Box 24, Folder 515)
    - Royal University of Ireland Diploma: Bachelor of Arts degree 1902 Oct 31 (Box 24, Folder 516)
    - Branch Medical Council for Ireland Certificate of Registration in the Medical Students' Register 1902 Oct 2 (Box 24, Folder 517)
    - Contract between James Joyce and Elkin Mathews CHAMBER MUSIC 1907 Jan 17 (cancelled) Accompanied by a typed transcript Gift of J. W. Warrington, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 518)
    - Contract between James Joyce and Grant Richards DUBLINERS 1914 Mar 20 (Box 24, Folder 519)
    - Contract between James Joyce and Grant Richards EXILES 1914 Aug 31 (Box 24, Folder 520)
    - Catalogue of a collection containing manuscripts & rare editions of James Joyce ... Belonging to Miss Sylvia Beach and offered for sale at her shop, Shakespeare and Company, 12, Rue de L'Odeon, 12 Paris-VI (Box 24, Folder 521)
    - Misc. (Box 24, Folder 522)
  - RECORDINGS
    Three recordings of James Joyce reading Anna Livia
    Plurabelle have been transferred to the Historical
    Sound Recordings Department of the Sterling Library.
- SERIES IV. SLOCUM AND CAHOON MATERIAL (1931-1966), 1931-66; (16 boxes)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Abbott, Berenice 1947 1 Slocum (Box 25, Folder 523)
    - Abbott, Charles D.
      See: University of Buffalo Library, Box 25, folder 527
    - Abramson, Ben
      See: Argus Books, Box 25, folder 523
    - Adams, F. B., Jr. 1948-1949 10 Slocum
    - Albert, Leonard 1950 4 Slocum
    - Allan, Ralph 1948-1950 2 Slocum
    - American Broadcasting Co. 1950 3 Slocum
    - Analytical Psychology Club 1949 2 Slocum
    - Anderson, Chester G. 1958 3 Cahoon
    - Archibald, R. C. 1953 3 Cahoon
    - Argus Books 1951 3 Cahoon
    - Argus Books 1949-1951 21 Slocum Accompanied by 1 TLS from Samuel Roth to Ben Abramson.
    - Armstrong, Edwin R.
      See: Box 25, Folder 542
    - Australia. Mitchell Library 1948 5 Slocum
    - Armstrong, Edwin R. 1949-1950 41 Slocum Correspondence about a production of Finnegans Wake. Includes correspondence with Howard S. Cullman and James Sweeney. (Box 25, Folder 524)
    - Baker, Elma 1950 3 Slocum (Box 25, Folder 525)
    - Baker, George 1950-1951 2 Slocum
    - Baker, James 1950 2 Slocum
    - Bancroft, Henrietta N.
      See: Analytical Psychology Club, Box 25, folder 523
    - Bancroft, Mary 1948 1 Slocum
    - Bayne, Hugh A. 1951 3 Slocum
    - Beach, Sylvia 1947-51 23 Slocum
      Accompanied by a TLS from Sylvia Beach to Crosby
      Gaige (1928 May 3, Paris ) and a TLS from Sylvia
      Beach to Jacob Schwartz ( 1930 Jan 13, Paris)
    - Benco, Sylvio 1948 1 Slocum
    - Benjamin, Mary A. 1947 1 Slocum
    - Berger, René 1948-1949 2 Slocum
    - Bernstein, Maurice 1950 1 Slocum
    - Berti, Luigi 1951 1 Slocum
    - Bettex, Albert No date 1 Cahoon
    - Birge, Walter W., Jr. 1948-1949 6 Slocum
    - Bissex, Henry S. 1951 2 Slocum
    - B. H. Blackwell, Ltd. 1951 5 Slocum
    - Haskell M. Block 1950-1951 6 Slocum
    - Bodleian Library 1950 2 Slocum (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Boesen, Charles S. 1948 6 Slocum
    - Boisen, Peter M. 1954 1 Cahoon
    - Boisen, Peter M. 1950 2 Slocum
    - Bollingen Series 1966 1 Cahoon
    - Bookings Corp. 1936 1 Roberts
    - Boston Public Library 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Boston Public Library 1950 2 Slocum
    - Bowes, Fred 1956 1 Cahoon (Box 25, Folder 527)
    - R. R. Bowker Co. 1951 1 Cahoon
    - Branchauer, Edmund 1948-1950 3 Slocum
    - Brewer, Joseph 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Brinnan, John 1947 3 Slocum
    - British Book Centre 1950 3 Slocum
    - British Broadcasting Co. 1950 3 Slocum
    - British Museum 1950 5 Slocum
    - Britschgi & Pinkus 1948 1 Slocum
    - Brown University Library
      See: Archibald, R. C., Box 25, folder 523
    - Bruce Publishing Co. 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Buchman, Alexander H. 1950-1951 13 Slocum
    - Budgen, Frank 1948-1950 28 Slocum
    - University of Buffalo Library 1953-1955 2 Cahoon
    - University of Buffalo Library 1950-1951 5 Slocum
    - Byrne, John Francis 1949-1950 3 Cahoon
    - Byrne, John Francis 1949-1951 14 Slocum
    - Cahoon, Herbert 1947-1956 55 Slocum (Box 25, Folder 528)
    - Cairns, Huntington 1950-1951 5 Slocum (Box 25, Folder 529)
    - California. University at Berkeley 1946-1949 12 Slocum
    - Camerino, Aldo 1948 3 Slocum
    - Carlson, N. V. 1947-1953 12 Slocum The first two letters are to Roberts.
    - Jonathan Cape 1955-1956 3 Cahoon
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace 1938 5 Cahoon
    - Carroll, John M.
      See: Boston Public Library, Box 25, folder 526
    - Carter, John 1949 2 Slocum
    - Casanova, Mrs. Telesforo 1951 2 Slocum
    - Cecchi, Emilio 1947 3 Slocum
    - Charles, David 1948 1 Slocum
    - Chaucer Head Book Shop 1950 1 Slocum
    - Chillag, Charles 1953 1 Cahoon
    - Chiswick Book Shop 1950 1 Slocum
    - Clancy, Mrs. George 1950 2 Slocum
    - Cleveland Public Library 1949 5 Cahoon
    - Collamore, H. Bacon 1938-1939 6 Slocum (Box 25, Folder 530)
    - Clongowes Woods College 1950 1 Slocum
    - Collet, Georges-Paul 1950-1951 7 Slocum
    - Colum, Padraic 1949 2 Slocum
    - Columbia Broadcasting Co. 1950-1951 3 Slocum
    - Columbia University Library 1938 4 Slocum
    - Columbia University Press 1949-1950 4 Slocum
    - Connolly, Thomas E. 1955 3 Cahoon
    - Connor, Clarence 1950 2 Slocum
    - Croessmann, H. K. 1953-1956 15 Cahoon
    - Croessmann, H. K. 1948-1959 31 Slocum
    - Cullman, Howard S.
      See: Armstrong, Edwin R., box 25, folder 524
    - Cunningham, M. Wayne 1957 1 Cahoon
    - Curran, Constantine P. 1947-1949 6 Slocum
    - Damon, S. Foster 1948 2 Slocum (Box 25, Folder 531)
    - Deharme, Lise 1950 1 Slocum
    - Dennis, Mrs. Frederic J. 1947 4 Slocum
    - Deutsch, B. 1953 1 Cahoon
    - Devin-Adair Co. 1951 2 Slocum
    - Dial Press 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Diamond, David 1950 2 Slocum
    - Diamond, Elizabeth E. 1949 1 Cahoon
    - Didier Publishers 1951 2 Slocum
    - Diebold, Inc. 1948 2 Slocum
    - Dodge, Marvin 1951 2 Slocum
    - Döblin, Alfred 1949 1 Cahoon
    - Dooher, J. Murdoch 1950 2 Slocum
    - Doubleday 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Drake, Joseph F. 1948-1950 7 Slocum
    - Dublin University. Trinity College 1954 1 Slocum
    - Duchnes 1948 2 Slocum
    - Dwiggins, William A. 1950 4 Slocum
    - Ecclesine, Mrs. Marcella 1949 3 Slocum (Box 26, Folder 532)
    - Edwards, John H. 1950-1951 5 Slocum
    - Einaudi 1948 2 Slocum
    - Elkin Mathews, Ltd.
      See: Mathews, Box 37, folder 539
    - Ellmann, Richard 1952-1959 34 Cahoon
    - Ellmann, Richard 1948-1950 6 Slocum
    - Erlanger, Mrs. Milton 1950-1951 3 Slocum
    - Esperanto 1952 1 Cahoon
    - Eleftheroudakis
      See: Greece, Box 26, folder 533
    - Faber & Faber, Ltd. 1947-1950 10 Slocum
    - Farrar, Straus & Young 1954 1 Cahoon
    - Fellheimer, Jeannette 1951 2 Slocum
    - Finnanger, Mrs. H. 1951 1 Cahoon
    - Fitelberg, Grzegorz 1950 3 Slocum
    - Fletcher, Ifan Kyrie 1950 2 Slocum
    - Ford, William J. 1949-1950 5 Slocum
    - French & European Publications 1947 3 Slocum
    - Friar, Kimon
    - Friede, Donald 1938-1950 5 Slocum
    - Gaige, Crosby 1939 1 Slocum (Box 26, Folder 533)
    - Gallup, Donald 1950-1953 2 Cahoon
    - Gerhard, Arthur 1951 2 Slocum
    - Gerson, Henry 1948-1951 23 Slocum
    - Giedion-Welcker, Carola 1947-1950 6 Slocum
    - Gilbert, Stuart 1948-1950 18 Slocum
    - Gillet, D. 1949 3 Slocum
    - Glasheen, Mrs. Francis 1953 1 Cahoon
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John 1948 2 Slocum
    - Golden Eagle Press 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Goodspeed's 1950-1951 11 Slocum
    - Gorman, Mrs. Herbert 1956 1 Cahoon
    - Gorman, Herbert 1950-1951 9 Slocum
    - Gotham Book Mart 1939-1950 6 Slocum
    - Greacen, Mrs. Patricia 1949-1950 Slocum
    - Greece 1947 9 Slocum About Joyce's works in Greek. Various correspondents.
    - Greene's Library 1949-1950 7 Slocum
    - Griffin, Kathleen 1949-1950 3 Slocum
    - Griswold, Mrs. Frank T. 1949 2 Slocum
    - Hamill & Barker 1948 2 Slocum (Box 26, Folder 534)
    - Hanley, T. E. 1949-1955 21 Cahoon
    - Hanley, T. E. 1950 31 Slocum
    - Harkness, Bruce 1954 2 Cahoon
    - Rupert Hart-Davis 1952 1 Cahoon
    - Harvard 1951-1956 4 Cahoon
    - Harvard 1939-1951 54 Slocum
    - Hayden, Violet 1948 4 Slocum
    - Hayes, R. J.
      See: Ireland. National Library, Box 26, folder 535
    - Healey, James A. 1948-1950 17 Slocum
    - Healey, George 1957 1 Cahoon
    - W. Heffer & Sons 1947 1 Slocum
    - Heine, Arthur 1951 1 Slocum
    - Hetherington, G. E. 1949 2 Slocum
    - Higginson, Fred H. 1953 3 Slocum
    - Hirshman, Mrs. H. 1946-1949 5 Slocum
    - Hodges, Figgis & Co. 1949 3 Slocum
    - Hollings, Frank 1950 2 Slocum
    - House of Books 1946-1949 6 Slocum
    - Hudson Review 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Hudson Review 1949 3 Slocum
    - Huebsch, B. W.
      See: Viking Press, Inc., Box 29, folder 554
    - Bruce Humphries, Inc. 1950 3 Slocum
    - Hungarian Book Service 1949 1 Cahoon
    - International Book Service 1949 5 Slocum (Box 26, Folder 535)
    - International Book Society 1950 1 Slocum
    - International Business Machine Corp. 1952 1 Cahoon
    - Ireland, National Library 1948-1951 40 Slocum
    - Irish Agricultural Society 1948-1949 5 Slocum
    - Istituto Editoriale Italiano 1949 1 Slocum
    - Jackson, William M.
      See: Harvard, Box 26, folder 534
    - Jolas, Maria 1941-1950 25 Slocum
    - Jonsson, Thorsten 1948 1 Slocum
    - Joyce, Giorgio 1949 1 Slocum
    - Joyce, Nora 1949 1 Slocum
    - Joyce, Stanislaus 1948-1951 53 Slocum
    - Kagen, Sergius 1952 1 Cahoon (Box 26, Folder 536)
    - Kain, Richard
      See: Folder 537
    - Kajima, Sho 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Kaplan, Maurice 1949-1950 25 Slocum
    - University of Kansas 1953 4 Cahoon
    - Keisogloff, Peter 1949-1950 5 Slocum
    - Kelleher, John 1948 4 Slocum
    - Kennedy, J. J. 1950 4 Slocum
    - Kenner, M. Hugh 1950 6 Slocum
    - Kennerly, Mitchell 1947 2 Slocum
    - Keynes, Quentin 1947-1949 14 Slocum
    - Klein, A. M. 1947-1951 23 Slocum
    - Koch, Vivienne 1949 5 Slocum
    - Krause, Friederich 1947 14 Slocum
    - Kain, Richard 1949-1956 24 Cahoon (Box 26, Folder 537)
    - Kain, Richard 1947-1954 61 Slocum
    - John Lane 1949-1950 8 Slocum (Box 27, Folder 538)
    - Laughlin, James 1947-1951 22 Slocum
    - Lawrence, Dan H. 1954 3 Cahoon
    - Léon, Mrs. Paul 1947-1951 34 Slocum Includes a carbon of her "The Story of a Friendship."
    - Levin, Harry 1940-1955 13 Slocum
    - Liber, Amour F. 1951 1 Slocum
    - Library of Congress 1947-1951 9 Slocum
    - Libreria Internazionale 1948-1949 2 Slocum
    - Libris (London) 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Libros Porter 1950 2 Slocum
    - Linati, Carlo 1947 10 Slocum
    - Lanier, Henry W. 1938 1 Slocum
    - Lopez-Ballesteros, Luiz 1952 1 Slocum
    - McAlmon, Robert 1947-1953 6 Slocum (Box 27, Folder 539)
    - MacCarvill, Eileen 1957-1958 8 Cahoon
    - MacDonald, James 1950 3 Slocum
    - MacGregor, Robert 1955-1957 8 Cahoon
    - McHugh, Roger 1948-1951 13 Slocum
    - MacLeish, Archibald 1950 2 Slocum
    - The Macmillan Co. 1950 2 Cahoon
    - Magalaner, Marvin 1951-1962 19 Cahoon
    - Magalaner, Marvin 1950 8 Slocum
    - Magnum Photos 1948-1949 5 Slocum
    - Maguire, S. J. No date 1 Slocum
    - Mann, Mrs. C. H. Adolph 1950 3 Slocum
    - Marks, Harry F. 1938 2 Slocum
    - Martin's Book Shop 1951 1 Slocum
    - Mason, Ellsworth
      See: Folder 540
    - Mason, Harold 1948 1 Slocum
    - Elkin Mathews, Ltd. 1949-1953 11 Slocum
    - Meenan, James 1950 4 Slocum
    - Mills, Richard L. 1951 1 Cahoon
    - Miner, Paul 1954-1955 4 Cahoon
    - Monahan, François 1949 2 Slocum
    - Monahan, May 1951 3 Slocum
    - Monro, Saw & Co. 1947 14 Slocum
    - More, Trenchard 1950 5 Slocum
    - Morison, Mary 1950 5 Slocum
    - Morse, J. Mitchell 1958 2 Cahoon
    - Moura, Antonio 1953 1 Cahoon
    - Mutual Broadcasting Co. 1950 3 Slocum
    - Mason, Ellsworth 1949-1956 27 Cahoon (Box 27, Folder 540)
    - Mason, Ellsworth 1948-1956 66 Slocum
    - Nathan, Fritz 1948 1 Slocum (Box 27, Folder 541)
    - National Broadcasting Co. 1950-1951 7 Slocum
    - New York Herald Tribune 1951 1 Slocum
    - New York Public Library 1948-1950 3 Slocum
    - New York Times 1951 1 Slocum
    - The New Yorker 1952 1 Cahoon
    - Noel, Lucie
      See: Mrs. Paul Léon, Box 27, folder 538
    - Norway. National Library 1952-1953 2 Slocum
    - Notes and Queries 1952 1 Cahoon
    - O'Hegarty, P. S. 1947-1951 28 Slocum (Box 27, Folder 542)
    - O'Kelly, Sean T. 1948 1 Slocum
    - O'Sullivan, P. 1949 2 Slocum
    - Painter, George D.
      See: British Museum, Box 25, folder 527
    - Palmer, Mrs. T. No date 1 Slocum (Box 27, Folder 543)
    - Parks, Roy Hill 1948 1 Slocum
    - Parelhoff, Albert D. 1951 1 Cahoon
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes 1955 1 Cahoon
    - Perkins, P. D.
      See: Folder 544
    - Perrins, Neil 1949 3 Slocum
    - Pertzoff, Peter 1949-1950 4 Slocum
    - Philpotts, Edith
      See: Irish Agricultural Society, Box 26, folder 535
    - Poggioli, Renato 1948-1950 30 Slocum
    - Polish Research and Information Service 1950 2 Slocum
    - Polsky, Ned 1951 2 Slocum
    - Porter, Jack 1950 1 Slocum
    - Potter, Jack 1949-1950 7 Slocum
    - Pracontal, Diane de 1949 1 Slocum
    - Prescott, Joseph
      See: Folders 545-46
    - Presser, Theodore 1950 1 Slocum
    - Princeton Library 1950 5 Cahoon
    - Princeton Library 1950-1951 12 Slocum
    - Perkins, P. D. 1937 5 Roberts Accompanied by a list of articles and books about the works of James Joyce in Japanese. (Box 27, Folder 544)
    - Prescott, Joseph 1950-1957 46 Cahoon (Box 27, Folder 545)
    - Prescott, Joseph 1938-1950 44 Slocum (Box 27, Folder 546)
    - Ramakrisha & Sons 1950 1 Slocum (Box 28, Folder 547)
    - Randall, David 1950 1 Slocum
    - Random House 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Random House 1950-1951 8 Slocum
    - Ratton, Charles 1949-1950 3 Slocum
    - Reece, Holroyd 1948-1950 2 Slocum
    - Reid, Nancy No date 1 Slocum
    - Reynolds, Horace 1939 2 Slocum
    - Grant Richards, Ltd. 1947 9 Slocum
    - Rinehart & Co. 1950 2 Slocum
    - Roberts, George 1948 1 Slocum (Box 28, Folder 548)
    - Roberts, R. F. 1941-1951 35 Slocum
    - Rockfell, Baily Co. 1949 3 Slocum
    - Rockwell, Kenneth 1950 2 Slocum
    - Rogers, Derek 1948 2 Cahoon
    - Root, Waverly 1950 1 Slocum
    - Rosenbach Co. 1950 2 Slocum
    - Rota, Bertram
      See: Folder 549
    - Roth, Samuel 1950-1951 5 Slocum
    - Rothe, Hans 1951 6 Slocum
    - Rousseau, Theodore 1950-1951 5 Slocum
    - Rowe, Stanley 1954 1 Slocum
    - Roy Publishers 1947 2 Slocum
    - Ruggiero, Paul 1931 3 Slocum Accompanied by a carbon copy of Remembrances of James Joyce.
    - Ryf, Robert S. 1956 1 Cahoon
    - Rota, Bertram 1948-1951 84 Slocum Accompanied by invoices for purchases made by John Slocum. (Box 28, Folder 549)
    - Savitsky, Ludmila 1950 1 Slocum (Box 28, Folder 550)
    - Scheuer, E. 1951-1953 2 Cahoon
    - Scheuer, E. 1950 7 Slocum
    - Scholes, Robert E. 1959 5 Cahoon
    - Schorer, Mark 1950 2 Slocum
    - Schwartz, Jacob 1952 4 Cahoon
    - Schwartz, Jacob 1937-1948 12 Slocum
    - Scribner's 1950 1 Cahoon
    - Scribner's 1938-1950 6 Slocum
    - Scribner's 1947 1 Roberts
    - Segerman, Elizabeth 1951 2 Slocum
    - Selig, Karl Ludwig 1952-1953 3 Cahoon
    - Serly, Tibor 1950-1951 3 Slocum
    - Settanni, Ettore 1950 1 Slocum
    - Seven Gables 1948-1950 2 Slocum
    - Shaw, Leroy R. 1956 2 Cahoon
    - Sheridan, Monica 1949 2 Slocum
    - Sheridan, Niall 1948-1951 11 Slocum
    - Singer, Forest D. 1951 1 Slocum
    - Sorel, Mabel Worthington 1955 4 Cahoon
    - Southern Illinois University Press 1959 1 Cahoon
    - Speiser, Maurice J. 1947 2 Slocum
    - Spoerri, James F. 1956 1 Roberts
      See also: Folders 551-552
    - Sotheby & Co. 1948 2 Slocum
    - Soupault, Philippe 1950 6 Slocum
    - Stanford University 1958 1 Cahoon
    - Starkey, James S. 1948-1950 8 Slocum
    - Steinberg, Erwin 1952 1 Cahoon
    - Steinglass, Meyer 1948 4 Slocum
    - Steloff, Frances See: Gotham Book Mart
    - C. A. Stonehill, Inc. 1938-1948 3 Slocum
    - Straumann, Heinrich 1950 3 Slocum
    - Sumner, John S. 1950 5 Slocum
    - Sweeney, James J. 1948-1951 6 Slocum For other correspondence between Sweeney and John Slocum
      See: EXHIBITIONS OF SLOCUM MATERIAL, Harvard Exhibition (1941), Box 30, folder 558
    - Sy, Edwin Albert 194.9-1951 5 Slocum
    - Spoerri, James F. 1949-1965 139 Cahoon (Box 28, Folder 551)
      See also: Folder 550
    - Spoerri, James F. 1948-1953 171 Slocum Accompanied by a carbon copy of a catalogue of Mr. Spoerri's Joyce collection. (1953) (Box 28, Folder 552)
    - Tschann, Louis 1950 7 Slocum (Box 29, Folder 553)
    - Thompson, John 1939-1951 10 Slocum
    - Time Magazine 1947-1950 5 Slocum
    - Tindall, William 1951-1956 11 Cahoon
    - Titus, Edward 1948 2 Slocum
    - Treanor, Walter 1949-1950 20 Slocum
    - Treharne, Maude 1950 3 Cahoon
    - Trinity College 1950 3 Slocum
    - Tucci, Niccolo 1950 1 Slocum
    - Tuttle, Charles 1947 1 Roberts
    - Tuttle, Charles 1949-1952 12 Slocum
    - Van Doren, Mark 1950 1 Slocum (Box 29, Folder 554)
    - Vanguard Press 1948 3 Slocum
    - Vietor, Glen 1951 1 Slocum
    - Viking Press 1947-1951 22 Slocum
    - Vitelli, G. 1949 2 Slocum
    - Von Phul, Ruth 1956 1 Cahoon
    - Von Weber, Roland 1948 2 Slocum
    - Wade, Allan 1953 1 Cahoon (Box 29, Folder 555)
    - Walbridge, Emil 1953 1 Cahoon
    - Watson, George 1957 2 Cahoon
    - Wayne, R. 1949 1 Cahoon
    - Wayne, R. 1948-1949 3 Slocum
    - Weaver, Harriet Shaw 1947-1952 90 Slocum
    - Wells, James R. 1947 5 Slocum
    - West, Walter Y. 1950 1 Slocum
    - Westermann Co. 1940 1 Slocum
    - Weyhe, E. 1948 1 Slocum
    - White, William 1953 3 Cahoon
    - White, William 1948-1949 7 Slocum
    - Whitside, George W. 1950 1 Slocum
    - Whyte Bookshop 1950 2 Slocum
    - Willard Art Gallery 1947-1950 5 Slocum
    - Williams Book Store 1949 1 Slocum
    - Wilson, Edmund 1953 2 Cahoon
    - Wilson, Laura M. 1947 4 Slocum
    - University of Wisconsin 1950 1 Slocum
    - Womack, H. Lynn 1951 1 Cahoon
    - YM & YWHA 1949-1950 3 Slocum (Box 29, Folder 556)
    - Jake Zeitlin, Inc. 1938-1950 5 Slocum
  - EXHIBITIONS OF SLOCUM COLLECTION MATERIAL
    - Paris Exhibition and sale (1949-1950) Correspondence between John J. Slocum and the following: La Hune Pierre Beres, Inc. Connor, Clarence Faramond, A. de Harl, Robert Harvard Jolas, Maria Scribner Book Store Spoerri, James F. UNESCO Accompanied by lists of material lent to the exhibition and appraisals of material for sale. (Box 30, Folder 557)
    - Harvard Exhibition (1941) Northwestern Exhibitlon (1953) Princeton Exhibition (1950) (Box 30, Folder 558)
    - Institute of Contemporary Arts (London, 1950) Accompanied by photographs of the exhibition.
    - Yale Exhibition (1951) Accompanied by photographs of the exhibitlon. (Box 30, Folder 559)
  - JAMES JOYCE SOCIETY MATERIAL:
    - Bylaws, announcements of meetings, general policies. (Box 30, Folder 560)
    - Speeches:
      - Cahoon The Slocum Collection 1952 typescript Slocum On Stanislaus Joyce No date typescript (Box 30, Folder 561)
    - Correspondence:
      - Albert, Leonard 1950 2 Slocum Block, Haskell 1950 2 Slocum Cahoon, Herbert 1949 1 Slocum Edel, Leon 1956 2 Cahoon Edel, Leon 1949-1950 13 Slocum Epstein, Edmund 1956 1 Cahoon Kiel, Muriel 1950 3 Slocum McGritt, Malcom 1956 1 Cahoon Moos, Elizabeth 1948 2 Slocum Porter, Andrew J. 1950 5 Slocum Roberts, R. F. 1941 1 Slocum Troy, William No date 1 Cahoon Wilder, Thornton 1949 1 Cahoon Wilder, Thornton 1949 4 Slocum Wilson, Edmund 1950 2 Slocum (Box 30, Folder 562)
  - NOTES AND LISTS MADE FOR THE BIBLIOGRAPHY
    - Notes on index cards (Box 31, Folder 563)
    - 12 Notebooks with miscellaneous notes (Box 32, Folder 564-66)
    - Miscellaneous Lists [folders 1-4] (Box 33, Folder 567-70)
    - Miscellaneous Lists [folders 1-3] (Box 33, Folder 571-73)
  - PUBLICATION DETAILS FOR THE BIBLIOGRAPHY
    - Correspondence: 69 letters dated from 1947 to 1953, by the following: Herbert Cahoon John J. Slocum Yale University Press Norman Holmes Pearson Donald Gallup Rupert Hart-Davis (Box 34, Folder 574)
    - Contract between the Yale University Press and John J. Slocum, 1953. (Box 34, Folder 575)
    - Preliminary typescript. (Box 34, Folder 576)
    - Galley proofs corrected by John Hayward in London for the London edition printed by Rupert Hart-Davis, 1953. (Box 34, Folder 577)
    - Galley proofs corrected by Herbert Cahoon for the Yale University Press edition, 1953. (Box 34, Folder 578)
    - Reviews (Box 34, Folder 579)
  - MATERIAL FROM JOYCE SCHOLARS (CAHOON)
    - Joyce - chronology notes (Box 34, Folder 580)
    - Bryson, Lyman, et al.; "Invitation to Learning: Ulysses," typescript, 1947 Dec 28 (Box 34, Folder 581)
    - Joyce, James; "James Clarence Mangan," [unpublished], translated by Jeanette Fellheimer, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 582)
    - Joyce, James; "Ireland-Island of Saints and Sages," [unpublished], holograph and typescript (Box 34, Folder 583)
    - Klein, A.M.; "[Joyce] Letters to Ellsworth Mason," typescript carbon, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 584)
    - Prescott, Joseph; "James Joyce's Ulysses as a Work in Progress," typescript, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 585)
    - Schwartz, Jacob; "Remarks on Joyce," typescript, 1951 Oct 23 (Box 34, Folder 586)
    - Slocum, John J.; [talk at a poetry center, Y.M.H.A.], typescript, 1950 Feb 9 (Box 34, Folder 587)
    - Sykes, Claud W.; "Recollections of James Joyce," typescript, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 588)
    - von Weber, Roland; "On and about James Joyce's Exiles," typescript (Box 34, Folder 589)
- SERIES V. SLOCUM & CAHOON MATERIAL (1967-1993), (3 boxes)
  This series contains miscellaneous materials
  collected at the Beinecke Library after the
  collection was originally processed. It consists
  of three subseries, each arranged alphabetically.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Correspondence about Joyce Collection, 1972-86 (Box 35, Folder 590)
      [includes Herbert Cahoon, Philip K.
      Cohen
    - Form letter from Joyce Fund, 1941 Feb 15 (Box 35, Folder 591)
    - Letter from Joyce to Frank Budgen [transcript], typescript, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 592)
    - Letters to Herbert Cahoon, 1952-66 (Box 35, Folder 593)
      [includes: Jack Dalton, N. L. Hyman,
      Lindley Hubbell, and Bill McGuire]
    - Letters from Paul Leon
      - To Ralph Pinker, 1934 (Box 35, Folder 594)
      - To Michael Healy, 1934
    - Letter to John Slocum from Patricia Greacan, 1950 Jul 21 (Box 35, Folder 595)
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Articles by Joyce from Il Piccolo della Serra translated by Lindley Williams Hubbell, typescript (Box 35, Folder 596)
    - Clippings on various subjects, ca. 1960s-80s (Box 35, Folder 597-98)
    - Material received from the estate of Harriet Weaver, including: Press releases for Joyce publications, Obituary of Margaret Anderson, Photocopy of article on Joyce by Thornton Wilder, Letter from Monro Pennefather & Co. to Yale University, 1973 Jan 9, Letter from Richard Ellmann to Marjorie Wynne, 1973 Sep 14, Letter from Ezra Pound to John Slocum, [ca. late 1940s] (Box 35, Folder 598a)
    - Miscellaneous notes used for BIBLIOGRAPHY OF JAMES JOYCE, ca. 1930s-50s (Box 35, Folder 599)
    - Notes on and transcriptions of Joyce letters to Michael Healy, Frank Budgen, and Ezra Pound (Box 35, Folder 600)
    - Photographs of Joyce and manuscript (Box 35, Folder 601)
  - WRITINGS ABOUT JOYCE